<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>eloise.rip - Tech</title><link href="https://eloise.rip/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://eloise.rip/feeds/tech.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://eloise.rip/</id><updated>2026-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle>wintertime goblin hole 🕳❄</subtitle><entry><title>Hearing Age Guesser: How Old Are Your Ears?</title><link href="https://eloise.rip/blog/hearing-age-guesser-how-old-are-your-ears.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2026-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:eloise.rip,2026-02-20:/blog/hearing-age-guesser-how-old-are-your-ears.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Introducing a playful web app that estimates your hearing age by sweeping a tone from 8–20 kHz. Try it and see how your ears compare!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Is the Hearing Age Guesser?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hearing Age Guesser is a simple web app that lets you test your high-frequency hearing and estimate your "hearing age." It sweeps a sine tone from 8 kHz up to 20 kHz, and you tap the button when you stop hearing the sound. The app then calculates your estimated hearing age based on the last audible frequency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Did I Build This?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted a fun, accessible way to visualize hearing loss and make science approachable. Most people lose the ability to hear high frequencies as they age, but it's hard to notice day-to-day. This app makes it easy to check, share, and compare with friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactive Gauge:&lt;/strong&gt; Watch the needle sweep as the tone rises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Waveform Options:&lt;/strong&gt; Try sine, square, sawtooth, or triangle waves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accessible UI:&lt;/strong&gt; Large buttons, monospaced age display, and keyboard-friendly controls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matte, beveled buttons:&lt;/strong&gt; Subtle textures for a tactile feel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile Friendly:&lt;/strong&gt; Works on phones and tablets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How It Works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press "Start" to begin the sweep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listen for the tone as it rises in frequency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press "Stop" when you can no longer hear it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The app estimates your hearing age and displays it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Science Behind It&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human hearing typically ranges from 20 Hz to 20 kHz, but most adults can't hear above 15–17 kHz. The app uses published age-frequency curves to estimate age from the last audible frequency. It's not a medical test, but it's surprisingly accurate for a quick check!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Try It Yourself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/hearing-age-guesser.html"&gt;hearing-age-guesser.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Open Source &amp;amp; Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app is open source and built with Pelican, custom CSS, and JavaScript. If you have feedback or want to contribute, check out the &lt;a href="https://github.com/eloise-normal-name/eloise.rip"&gt;GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know your results! Did your ears surprise you?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="hearing"></category><category term="accessibility"></category><category term="webapp"></category><category term="audio"></category><category term="science"></category><category term="fun"></category></entry></feed>